<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Puney Chawla]]></title><description><![CDATA[Puney Chawla]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me/</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 18:32:52 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Domain Investing]]></title><description><![CDATA[What the heck is Domain Investing ?]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me//posts/domain-investing</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://swissknife.me//posts/domain-investing</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 17:40:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Today i read about something really interesting - Domain Investing. I stumbled upon it when going through this Genltleman&apos;s twitter Profile - &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/searchbound&quot;&gt;Peter Askew&lt;/a&gt;. One of his tweet caught my attention -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;You don&apos;t really need a business idea. All you really need is a great domain name. The domain can be your business inspiration.&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon i saw myself reading about his blog posts and understanding the world of Domain Investing. So here it is -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Domain Investing refers to making money through Domains. Now there are 3 ways you can make money off of Domains. They are :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flipping&lt;/strong&gt; - This refers to buying a Domain for a Cheaper Price and than selling them at a higher Price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Developing&lt;/strong&gt; - Here you buy a Domain that has some authority or is a search term that people naturally search for. An example of this would be : greenApples.com.. Here, once you acquire the domain you can carve out a niche for yourself and build a business.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parking&lt;/strong&gt; - Buying a Domain and setting up Ads on it to earn some money or using it to redirect to some other company and getting paid for Traffic or licensing the domain name. For this you should have a domain that naturally recieves a lot of traffic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the above ways require you to pick up a quality domain name like greenApples.com or codecamp.com, but the catch here is the majority of such domains have already been taken. How do you than go about finding them. One such way is to scan the Domains which will fall of the renewment cycle. This can be due to a person wanting to auction their domain or someone who just does not see value in the domain and would like to discontinue using it. Such domains are collected and listed on the Registrars like Godaddy daily. The trick is to spot the domain from there and bid for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is some complexities and terms involved like pre-release, deleted, The Drop etc in this trade, but the overarching point being to identify a quality domain and than use it to generate cash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Piece by Peter really helped me understanding the Industry and next time i am gonna land on some Domain i am not gonna pass by :P&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Update - Long time no write]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is a pretty short update since i wrote the last time.]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me//posts/update-long-time-no-write</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://swissknife.me//posts/update-long-time-no-write</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 17:40:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s been a long time since i wrote here.. I took a break from writing because i felt that i was writing the same things daily and i didn&apos;t have any novel thoughts / insights to write here. Honestly, i experienced a Brain Fog after leaving writing daily. So i have decided that i am going to commit to writing daily here again. Let&apos;s see how long can i continue !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the Updates, one big update is that i have left my job and now i am serving my notice period. I will not go over the reasons for leaving as i am not allowed to comment on them. The other update is that i am working on a small project on the side and it&apos;s something do do with Reddit. I will give more details as i progress on the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exercise is going great. I usually walk for 4 kms daily and than do 20 pushups plus some pull ups. I visited Ahmedabad city with my family and went to see some Jain Temples (I am not a Religious person but family outing was good.). Oh Also got a nice Haircut :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, now i will see you tomorrow. Cheers !&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Optimising 10% vs Optimising 90%]]></title><description><![CDATA[Now focussing on Optimising 90% of my time, which is spent in office work. My goal is to complete everything under 5 hrs daily.]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me//posts/optimising-10-percent-vs-optimising-90-percent</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://swissknife.me//posts/optimising-10-percent-vs-optimising-90-percent</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 17:40:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Its been a few days since i have started to seriously think about my habbits and pro-actively changing them for the better. For instance, i wake up at 7:00 am daily and go for a walk, than i exercise and do pushups and pull-ups. I also try to sit at my desk by 10:30 am so that i can start my office work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also frequently think about how can i optimise my time so that i can efficiently do all these things and not slack off. The first few days are the hardest TBH. But now, i am able to follow the exercise and walk part consistently. It is the Office work front where i slack off. Knowing that i can finish my work in 5 hrs, i tend to stretch it to 8 or 9 hrs. This is where most of the optimisation needs to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So instead of spending my time on optimising small tasks that merely take up 10% of my time, i am shifting my thought to optimising the large chunks, which take up 90% of my time. Historically, this has been the area which has been hardest for me to tackle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Work expands to fill the time Alloted&lt;/em&gt; - Parkinson&apos;s Law.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore i am going to limit my time of work. I am just going to do maximum work in a chunk of (11:00 am - 4:00 pm). No guitar, no checking of twitter, no fb, no news during this time. Only work. If it becomes too much i will take some break. The idea is to not pick any other task before i have my work completed and done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cool. Let me begin by putting my mobile away from my desk.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Naruto Sage Mode Unlocked !]]></title><description><![CDATA[Saturday - Party Night today ? Not Really.. Today i am feeling Super-Productive and amazing :)]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me//posts/naruto-sage-mode-unlocked</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://swissknife.me//posts/naruto-sage-mode-unlocked</guid><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 17:40:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;After completing 21 days of writing, i gave myself a break from writing daily to refresh my mind. While i may not be writing daily from now on, but i have decided that i am going to post any highlights or share any interesting thoughts or incidents i bump into. Though i will still make sure that i do that as often as i can. Anyways, let&apos;s jump into today&apos;s update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today i feel just like Naruto unleashing his sage mode. I am feeling Super Productive and focused today. This is what today looked like for me :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Woke Up Early today around 7:30 am (Yep that&apos;s early for me.. don&apos;t judge)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Went to a Park nearby and did some walking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While Walking i also did some catch up with my best friend (he lives in Toronto.. so we generally talk morning or nights)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meditated for 10 mins, failed at concentration.. but atleast i made time for it and tried.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did 15 Pushups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completed Pending Office Work in without wasting a lot of time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chilled by watching Silicon Valley Episodes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Went for another trip to the Park and completed 4 more rounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did 10 Pull-ups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrote this Article.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know, most of these talks are quite trivial and simple, but for me squeezing them daily has been a challenge. I am not able to keep up with health, Side-projects and office work daily. So days like these make me Super happy and Proud !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, I try to spend some time to observe my patterns in thinking, triggers, habbits and about Productivity. My goal is to be much more Consistent in Action and Objective in thinking / Decision making. I will keep on updating you all on how this Progresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TADA.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[21 days of Writing EveryDay !]]></title><description><![CDATA[A small appreciation post for me completing 21 days of writing daily.]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me//posts/21-days-of-writing-everyday</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://swissknife.me//posts/21-days-of-writing-everyday</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 17:40:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I just realised that yesterday i completed 21 days of, Writing Every day Challenge ! Wohoo !!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is often said in the Pop Culture that it takes 21 days to form a habbit, but i still don&apos;t feel that writing has become Natural to me or a habbit of mine. What has surely happened is that i have warmed up to the idea of writing and have become much more consistent in scheduling time for it. In other words, i have started prioritising writing amongst my other tasks for the day. Still i need to work a lot on my articulation. There is also always a question of what to write about.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Martian.]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today a fanboy of SpaceX is born !]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me//posts/the-martian</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://swissknife.me//posts/the-martian</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 17:40:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;img src = &quot;https://i.ibb.co/Yy9wB7T/starship.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SpaceX is one of the few companies that inspires me to dream big and bet on a brighter future. I recently saw the video of the SN8 Rocket launch and how it performed the belly flop Maneuver. The Video is just unbelievably cool. So today i spent sometime to research what is there progress and what are they currently working on ? A few interesting things which i liked about them were :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Their BIG, BOLD and Inspiring Mission. SpaceX wants to colonise Mars and make interplanetary transport affordable .&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on solving the Hardest Problems first. To make the Interplanetary transport affordable their biggest hurdle was to create a resuable rocket in order to significantly cut the costs. Their work for the better part of 2 decades has been just that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Science First. By this i meant that Elon deliberately chose not to make the company public and kept it sustaining through his money or finding commercial applications (Like delivering Cargo and Satellites). Making SpaceX Public, he said would not be the best thing as the investors requirements may not align with the mission of the company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hiring the Best of the Best. Self Evident.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed to be composable and Reusable. A lot of work was spent in designing of the Rockets so that parts could be swapped or capacity could be increased like adding blocks of lego on top of each other.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speed and Iterative Testing. Quite like the software world. SpaceX is rapidly testing the Starship with their SN6, SN7, SN8, SN9 and the latest SN10 prototypes. The launch tests happen frequently and data gathered from each one is used to improve the next one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can go on and on here. But What the people at SpaceX are doing is quite magical and feels like watching a sci-fi movie. The child in me can&apos;t wait to see the first man land on mars. It would be quite an Achievement of the Human Race. Thanks SpaceX for giving us all another reason to dream bigger !&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Clarity and Productivity]]></title><description><![CDATA[One of the causes of Being Unproductive is not having Clarity of Mind. Read to know more.]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me//posts/clarity-and-productivity</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://swissknife.me//posts/clarity-and-productivity</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 17:40:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I have noticed that sometimes i am unproductive because i don&apos;t have enough visibility on a task or my mind is not clear and is preoccupied with something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clarity comes from reducing the cognitive load. You can reduce it through Meditation, Planning, task subdividing or sorting your thoughts. It is a state of mind and can be altered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing is a highly effective way to get to a much more clear state of mind. It may also be thought of as &lt;em&gt;Brain Vomit&lt;/em&gt; because it has the same effects as that of puking after an upset stomach. Having a daily Routine is another way to reduce the cognitive load as there are lesser unknowns to think or pre-plan about. It is also why a lot of People do Visaulization exercises to paint the picture as clearly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[It Takes Time - Sid.]]></title><description><![CDATA[This Post is written to remind me to go easy on myself and it takes time to build anything substantial.]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me//posts/it-takes-time-sid</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://swissknife.me//posts/it-takes-time-sid</guid><pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 17:40:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;It Takes time to build something substantial. You won&apos;t have all the answers on day 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do a lot of our wishes remain a dream ? Maybe because we want to have everything right now. I am good at starting and getting into action when a idea strikes me, but the idea looses its fire gradually when i realise the amount of effort it requires to execute. When at times, i do follow through i would beat myself up for not knowing the answers to all the pieces of the puzzle upfront in a few hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is Frustating, but ultimately it is a way of thinking, &lt;strong&gt;which can be fixed&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today instead of saying - &quot;research and finalize everything today&quot; i said, let&apos;s look at 3 possible options today and 3 tomorrow and 3 day after tomorrow, Compile them in a sheet and at the end of a week or 2 we will analyse and pick the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This detaches you from 1 particular idea, gives you some breather and helps you develop a habbit to build and see things as a long iterative process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So &lt;strong&gt;BE CONSISTENT&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;TRUST THE PROCESS !&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[What did i Read Today - 12th Feb, 2021 ?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Some interesting Facts about Lithium Ion Batteries.]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me//posts/what-did-i-read-today-12-feb-2021</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://swissknife.me//posts/what-did-i-read-today-12-feb-2021</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 17:40:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;It is hard to come up with something new everyday, so i thought i would share about what i learned new today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lithium Ion Batteries :&lt;/strong&gt;
Some important points for the future of Batteries :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Prices of Lithium Ion Batteies have fallen more than 89% since 2010. In 2010 the Price was $1150/Kwh, whereas in 2021 the Price is around $135/Kwh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$100/Kwh is the magic number which will make EV&apos;s a viable option to the people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metal prices such as Lithium only account for 16% of total battery costs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;50% costs include the electrolyte, separator and assembly module.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Leading Producer of Lithium ion batteries is China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lithium has a high energy density so it can store a large amount of energy in a small volume.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The world reserves of Lithium are limited and are available for a decade only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, i am not very bullish on the Lithium Ion Battery technology. I am all for Batteries but it seems Lithium is not sustainable and we would have to search for some other alternative.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Quirk in Date Object in Javascript]]></title><description><![CDATA[Understand the difference in initializing a Date Object and produce fewer bugs!]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me//posts/quirk-in-date-object-in-javascript</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://swissknife.me//posts/quirk-in-date-object-in-javascript</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 17:40:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the difference between the output of these 2 lines of Javscript ?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;const date1 = new Date(&quot;2021-02-11&quot;);
const date2 = new Date(&quot;2021/02/11&quot;);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To answer this we need to understand how the Date constructor converts the string input to a Date Object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Date Object follows a certain set of Parsing guidelines (ISO 8601 etc) on how to parse the date string input. If you pass it in the YYYY-MM-DD, the parser tell it that this is a UTC Date string with the time as 00:00:00 if not provided. This can be verified by looking at the following output in your console window :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;new Date().toISOString();
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here the output will be something like : &quot;2021-02-11T17:35:13.191Z&quot;, which is the same format as &quot;YYYY-MM-DD&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now in the second case when you provide hyphens (&quot;2021/02/11&quot;) the parser tells it that this is a Locale Time Format String. Hence this will create a date assuming that this string is the time in your local timezone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore the ouputs of the 2 lines will differ. Even the Dates will differ if, the UTC date is different than your local Date. This will help you the next time you are using the Date object in your app and think about the string implementation you are passing to the Date constructor and its effects.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Art of Valuation]]></title><description><![CDATA[Ever wondered how do you value things. Why is a company valued higher than another. Let's explore this topic today !]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me//posts/the-art-of-valuation</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://swissknife.me//posts/the-art-of-valuation</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 17:40:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, i checked the P/E ratio of Tesla, it was more than 1700 !. if you don&apos;t know what that means, here is a quick explanation :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P/E ratio refers to the ratio of the Price of a stock and its Earnings Per share (EPS). It gives a sense of the amount by which the market is ready to pay for that stock. Higher EPS generally means that the market anticipates the company to have a high growth in the near future. On the contrary it may also mean that a stock may be overpriced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lead me to thinking how do you value a stock. It surely can&apos;t be just from the balance sheets. Here comes Aswath Damodaran, a brilliant professor at Stern school of Business at NYU who teaches corporate Finance and valuation. I would recommend you to do checkout his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z5chrxMuBoo&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; on Valuation at Google. Here is what i thought was really interesting in his talk :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valuation is part Science and a lot of Art. To do a good Valuation you need to master storytelling as well as be good with Numbers. As a founder, you sell a grand vision of the future, a future which pushes the value of your Product / Service. As an Investor, you try to assess how likely is the company going to reach that vision. If the Company is likely to reach that vision or better exceeds it you value it higher. On the contrary if you see that there is nothing extra-ordinary about the business and the vision that the founder is selling is an overly optimistic one, you bring down the Valuation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s understand it with an Example of Tesla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Tesla first started out it projected itself as a luxury electric sportscar maker. The story told for it was that of a similar kind of a luxury sportscar. These sportscars are high margins but low volume. That&apos;s why the Valuation of Tesla was low. Gradually as the market warmed up to the idea of electric cars being equal or probably superior to their gasoline counterparts, Elon told a different story. If you look up at thw Website of Tesla you will find this :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tesla is accelerating the world&apos;s transition to sustainable energy with electric cars, solar and integrated renewable energy solutions for homes and businesses.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now consider the market of sustainable energy and compare it with the luxury car market. Arguably it is atleast x more if not 100x. This naturally pushes up the Valuation. The second part is the investors faith in Elon being able to execute the Vision. I would argue that to people Tesla represents an even more grandeur vision with driverless cars and a world of self-driving vehicles, where it will start to enter the domain of a software company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this change in narratives push up the Valuation. So if you want to value the company then put together a narrative of the future of this company and than try to rationalise of how much is realistically possible.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Between the 2 Armies !]]></title><description><![CDATA[The book of Gita opens up with Krishna driving the chariot of Arjuna between the 2 armies. Read to understand the allegory behind ->]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me//posts/between-the-2-armies</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://swissknife.me//posts/between-the-2-armies</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 17:40:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Over a period of time, i have noticed, that on some days i experience a need to consume content and on other days i just don&apos;t want to watch anything. This happens time to time, where i would just focus on one thig and consume content around that topic. Right now my interest has been captured by Mahabharata and Gita and the allegories behind their text. Here i share one such paragraph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The battlefield in Mahabharata was set in Kurukshetra. This war was fought between the cousins Pandavas and Kauravas. The war has started now, the armies from both the sides (Pandavas and the Kauravas) have gathered around. Our hero, Arjuna is accompanied by Krishna in his chariot. Arjuna, who was all ready and confident to fight suddenly starts shaking upon realising that after this war his cousins and family members will die. Arjuna, once the mighty warrior, now just stands there pathetically and powerless. Seeing this Krishna drives the chariot between the 2 armies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the opening scene of Gita. the Phrase &lt;strong&gt;Between the 2 armies&lt;/strong&gt; refers to thinking objectively. Coming to a place between the good (the Pandavas army) and the bad (the Kauravas army) and than doing the thing which is right. Cultivating such an objectivity in life is crucial to operating successfully. Doing our duty and saying what is right and not attaching too much emotion to a decision but rather thinking objectively will serve all of us well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a great Phrase to remind yourself whenever you are to make a decision -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Between the 2 Armies.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tearing down Barriers to Rocket Science.]]></title><description><![CDATA[India needs to update its policy and laws on Model Rocketry and promote a culture of Science Exploration.]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me//posts/tearing-down-barriers-to-rocket-science</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://swissknife.me//posts/tearing-down-barriers-to-rocket-science</guid><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 17:40:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;img src = &quot;https://i.ibb.co/JkSfvMK/rocket.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was quite impressed watching a guy on Youtube building Rockets in his backyard. I thought it was impossible to build your own rockets and only companies or government organisations with a lot of money could do that. And the Rocket that the guy built was not some low level firecracker type rocket. A quick show off for model Rocketry capability :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;Icarus was designed and built by students from the Embry-Riddle Future Space Explorers and Developers Society. This vehicle set the world record for highest altitude launch by a student team with an apogee of 37.8 miles (200,000 feet), with a maximum velocity of Mach 4.04.&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing this, i wanted to build my own rocket, so i started researching about any rocketry clubs in India and has anybody done anything Similar. On more research i found that the laws in India are not favourable to this kind of Exploration. The current laws are :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pottasium Nitrate which is a key ingredient used to build a solid fuel Rocket motor is not legal to buy as it is explosive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even if you did manage to get your hands on it, the quantity that you would require to build anything decent is not available without several permissions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to notify a range of government bodies the details of which are not clearly given anywhere.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although i understand the intent of the government to put these laws, which is to, prevent any terrorist activites, but straight up banning them is not the solution. I would request the government and all the agencies to please think about it again as it prevents Science and exploration, which are the key pillars of any country&apos;s growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barriers to entry for pursuing scientific projects should be minimised as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Changing Narratives - 1]]></title><description><![CDATA[Shifting the narrative from - A Person requesting for help vs How can i apply my learnings from the help that i provide ?]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me//posts/changing-narratives-1</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://swissknife.me//posts/changing-narratives-1</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 17:40:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Imagine a Sunday afternoon you planned to relax, but by the time weekend approaches you still have some leftover work to be completed. Now, imagine you suddenly recieve a text from a friend to help them in setting up their website. What would you do ? My first reaction was &quot;Damn ! What excuse should i make for not helping&quot;. I ignored the message for a while and thought about this situation. I asked myself a few questions :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q. How much office work do i have ? Is it urgent ?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. There wasn&apos;t much work. I was just inflating it to fill my time and doing it casually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q. What am i gonna do after completing the work ? Do i have any other commitments for the day ?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. The answer was probably spend some time with family and than watch youtube or some other pass-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q. Am i feeling this because i felt lazy ?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. Yes, was feeling lazy and didn&apos;t want to take that cognitive load to brainstorm with them. Also the prospect having to enter into a commitment of delivering a website while working alongside a job was the biggest reason of inaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q. If they approach me next week will i agree ?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. No. This has been a pattern where some of my work is spilled to the weekend. It happened the last 2 weeks as well and would happen next week also probably if left unchecked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q. What do all these questions mean ?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. This means leave the Website Request, i would not have time for even pursuing my own ideas. I really need to think about it with a more proactive mindset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realised that this attitude was preventing me from taking other opportunities and pursuing my ideas as i would close my weekend time. While it is important to chill, in my case i am just procrastinating and filling my time with the work as an excuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now i wanted to frame this request in a different format to empower myself. A format in which i was helping myself be better. I than thought, if i help them, i will be able to learn about the shopify and ecommerce ecosystem. This will not only be an additional skillset, but i may also be able to monetize this request in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So i would encourage you as well, if you are about to turn down a request, first think about, Is there any way this task would help me become better ? Can i use the learnings gained to my advantage in any way ?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[It's time to go out of Syllabus]]></title><description><![CDATA[My thoughts on how we can improve our Education system.]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me//posts/its-time-to-go-out-of-syllabus</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://swissknife.me//posts/its-time-to-go-out-of-syllabus</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 17:40:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I had just got off the phone with my best friend Neel and we were talking about the education system or the lack of it in India. Our Education system is based on the supposition that better grades means more learning. While this is true to some extent, it completely misses the aspects of creativity and exploration. Also the grading system commercializes the questions, by which i mean that fact based questions are preferred in an exam as they are easy to grade and verify. This is increasingly true where MCQ are asked as opposed to open ended subjective questions because the marking is easily done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improving and striving for a better Education is a fundamental driver of any countr&apos;s growth. It is equivalent to investing in human capital which will pay dividends in the long run. Here is a framework on how we can build a better version of it :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Price of the Education needs to be capped as otherwise we would not be able to provide it to everyone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Salaries of teachers should be competitive to the market rates of other similar professions. This will incentivize experienced veterans to join this role.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In order to cut down cost, we will have to have a curriculum which can be reproduced across the country without degrading the quality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metrics should be designed around the Engagement of students, the questions they ask and the quality of thought they put in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students should be encouraged to develop a value system. Teaching how to debate, respect other people&apos;s opinion, thinking from first principles and learning how to work in a team should be the main aim.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Schools should encourage students to explore and go as broad as possible with respect to learning about various desciplines. This directly helps us to put together a view of the world and is creatively very stimulating.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think India should really take a deep look at it&apos;s current state of Education systema nd it&apos;s sustainability in the long run with respect to the massive automation in the times to come.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bulls vs Bears]]></title><description><![CDATA[Be an Opportunist and invest when the market is high and even when the market is down.]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me//posts/bulls-vs-bears</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://swissknife.me//posts/bulls-vs-bears</guid><pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 17:40:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Last year, 2020, was a crazy year. Who would have thought that a Pandemic would break out ? Well to be honest i thought that it was just another flu and within a month things will be back to normal. Covid-19 has had some very interesting effects on the world, one of which is on the stock market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the Lockdown, a lot of Retail Investors like me and you joined the markets for the first time. The number of new accounts opened with the trading platforms have never been so high. Needless to say, a lot of us were complete noobs at investing, mostly doing speculation, in what seems like the greatest bull run. Sensex went from 25,000 in march to over 50,000 in feb 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In such a rally, i became a bear, expecting market to crash any day. In my head i was thinking, the market has already gone up almost 2 times it can&apos;t go up any further. I was expecting a correction. This was in October. But the market went even higher. Than i though maybe Markets will correct in November, but the markets won&apos;t stop. December and January also passed similarly, while i was waiting up on the sidelines waiting for the main course to arrive. The main course never arrived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a very important learning for me. Being bullish on the market pays off most of the time. Exceptions happen but they do occasionally. If you want to make money, being a bull will serve you well. All the time i was waiting for the main course to arrive, while i could have eaten the tasty snacks all this while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going Forward, i want to apply an Opportunist mindset. If the Market is in a bull run than find opportunities and invest. If the market is down than also find opportunities and invest. Don&apos;t just wait for the market to fall in order to invest, because chances are even if the market falls before your eyes you would expect it to fall further. So be an Opportunist !.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dogecoin and the billionaire Memer]]></title><description><![CDATA[A lot of retail Investers buy because of FOMO. Don't be one of them.]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me//posts/dogecoin-and-the-billionaire-memer</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://swissknife.me//posts/dogecoin-and-the-billionaire-memer</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 17:40:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;What would you do if you have a 100 billion dollars ? Probably not be spending time creating memes : P. Yes i am talking about our hero Elon. Elon has built a reputation for moving markets by just tweeting, so much so as 800%. Stocks and crypto just dance around on his tweets. Sometimes, i think i could make a fortune if only i would monitor his tweets and buy or sell based on that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was an ordinary day. I was working and i happen to see elon&apos;s tweet about Doge with a meme of rocket to the moon. It almost rang a bell in me to buy it as a couple of days it went over 800% from Elon&apos;s tweet. But i held back for sometime, thankfully to my rational brain. What happened than you ask ? FOMO, how can i loose an opportunity to make money, so i bought some doge. The story gets even more interesting as doge starts to go up and Elon&apos;s tweets keep getting weirder untill the final tweet where he jokes about his earlier tweet about Doge. Thankfully i had already exited the hype, realising that this is madness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My takeaway :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&apos;t let FOMO control you. If you are buying just because other people are buying and your only exit strategy from the trade is by timing the Market than boy, Good luck to you. Also Memes from Elon are fun !&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Building a Personal Brand Online]]></title><description><![CDATA[A tactical metric to gauge the Performance of your Blog.]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me//posts/building-a-personal-brand-online</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://swissknife.me//posts/building-a-personal-brand-online</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 17:40:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday i was watching a video Podcast by David Perell, Jack Butcher and Ana Fabrega. The Podcast was about &quot;How to create Personal Monopolies Online&quot;. I highly recommend this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VINZMrpPIg8&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; to anyone who doesn&apos;t know about this concept but interested in building an online Presence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example of a highly successfull Personal Monopoly is that of Tim ferris. He has an almost cult like following amongst his fans and is famously called as &quot;human guinea pig&quot;. The moment People connect with you and come to you for a particular type of content than you have built a great brand / Personal Monopoly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jack describes the attributes required in creating a Personal Monopoly as the following :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Competence - This is the value you provide to people with your skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curiosity - A Curious Person will naturally gather some insights from learning about very different things. These insights will expand his competence gradually.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personality - This is a big one. This cuts the competition and help you to carve your own niche. People only connect when they share some common values. It is a way to broadcast your values and your worldview. Thos who believe in your worldview will join you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you know that you have built a Brand ?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it is hard in the begining to get the feedback from people, i have a quick tactical test for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just look at the analytics of your website. If after reading your article somebody is tempted to see your &quot;About me&quot; section, chances are pretty high, that they are interested in knowing more about you !&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Creating Rockstar Tickets for your Product.]]></title><description><![CDATA[My 2 cents to creating better Tickets while developing a Product.]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me//posts/creating-rockstar-tickets-for-your-product</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://swissknife.me//posts/creating-rockstar-tickets-for-your-product</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 17:40:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;As a company grows in size and the Product starts getting complex, we realise that the patterns which we have been following till now, don&apos;t really scale up and are often inefficient. One of such patterns is while creating Issues / Tickets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Synqy, our Product goal uptill a quarter ago was building the Minimum set of features in order to onboard clients. While building the Product we would often find that the business goals and requirements used to change quite frequently. New business models would be introduced, ways of attribution would be changed, Entire Reports would be built and scrapped, new user roles were added and so on. In such a scenario our main focus was to optimise for the velocity, i.e., deliver the Product value as quickly as possible and iterate. In this situation we didn&apos;t impose the discipline of writing Tickets expansively and as detailed as possible, as a lot of it was done hands on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, our goals have shifted more towards giving our customers a worthful experience. In such a situation, it is very important to write tickets better so that it conveys exactly what value we bring to the Product and measure our improvement over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here is how you write Rockstar Tickets :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before Writing about any ticket, take some time out to think about the feature you would be delivering. Pro tip : Think from the point of a User and leave your Dev brain out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next, break the features down into smaller parts, where each part can be completed within a Sprint (1 week usually) and the parts are independent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go as specific into the Problem as you can. Example : if the feature is to &quot;delete an Order&quot;, you can say something like &quot;Allow the User to delete orders one by one from the Order Listing on the My Orders Page.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define the Sequence of Actions that the User expects in order to interact with the feature successfully. This will also be used while testing the feature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define all the Pre-requisites or Pre-conditions if any for the feature to be placed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lastly, define a Success metric for the feature. When will we say we have achieved the desired result.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although there is no fixed rule to writing tickets but following these points will help you to create better tickets and help you to think just a little bit more on the value that you, as a developer, will be providing to the Product and the Organisation. The best of the Tickets are one which remove ambiguity and are quite actionable.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Novel Ideas ? Not so much.]]></title><description><![CDATA[A lot of what we think about are the same old things and the novel thoughts are extremely rare.]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me//posts/novel-idea-not-so-much</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://swissknife.me//posts/novel-idea-not-so-much</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 17:40:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;With the challenge of writing 1 small post each day, i have noticed that there are very few original thoughts of mine. Before this challenge i thought, it was easier to write a post each day, as i always had something going on / brewing in my mind. But reflecting back now, it was mainly the same thougths that used to revolve over and over again in my mind. There were very few novel ideas and those depend mainly on the kind of content that i consume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, one of the benefits of writing a post everyday is getting clarity. When you write down your circle of thoughts down, the chatter settles down, as it knows that it has been fully given attention to. They keep vieing for our attention, pretty much as we all do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To keep continuing this Series of Posts, i have decided that i don&apos;t have to write a novel idea or an interesting thought. I give myself the liberty to write anything. From a simple observation to poetry, from a Interesting fact that i read to what&apos; on my mind. So here is today&apos;s observation :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OBSERVATION :
While reading a tweet i noticed that the Profile Picture of the Person in the tweet added a certain colour to my judgement of the tweet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also it is incredibly hard to work early morning during winters : P&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[8 Questions which Everyone should be able to Answer]]></title><description><![CDATA[It's time our School Curriculum catches up and Teach the real deal to the Students]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me//posts/8-questions-which-everyone-should-be-able-to-answer</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://swissknife.me//posts/8-questions-which-everyone-should-be-able-to-answer</guid><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 17:40:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Today i want to write about our Indian Education curriculum, in particular about the redundancy of school education. Consider the Most important of duties / skills / Knowledge that a working professional must have. I have listed a few below :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowing the basics of how to file your Taxes. What is Form 16 and form 26 AS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can i save taxes ? What is PPF and NPS ? What is Term Insurance ? What is Mediclaim ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basics of GST. What is ITC and how to claim it. How does a business operate ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading basic balance Sheets, Cash flow and Income Statements. How are businesses run (broad Level) ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does the Legal System work ? What are my Fundamental Rights ? How is a Litigation carried out ? How to register an FIR ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basics of Politics. Difference between the Left and the Right ? Democracy vs communism ? How to judge a candidate ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to think Objectively ? How to debate constructively ? Learn to see our Biases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does the Economy work in a broader scope ? Difference between bonds and Equity. Concept of Fractional Reserve banking and overview of Markets and some historical moments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly you can see how important these topics are, yet are schooling does a poor job in teaching us these extremely valuable and utmost practical concepts. I have even seen, grown up people just throwing jargon as an explanation to some of these questions, yet if you ask them questions, you would find they often know very little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The great thing about the above topics is that they naturally spark our curiosity to lean more as they are extremely practical. And once you ignite someone&apos;s mind, they will walk a 100 miles by themselves just to quench it.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Newsletters - An Interesting Marketing Avenue !]]></title><description><![CDATA[If you want to market a Product, try advertising on a newsletter.]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me//posts/newsletters-an-interesting-marketing-avenue</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://swissknife.me//posts/newsletters-an-interesting-marketing-avenue</guid><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 17:40:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;If you are someone like me, who likes to geek out about stuff, chances are you might have subscribed to a few newsletters. Sipping that Morning Tea and scrolling through your favorite newsletter feels incredible and primes you up for work after it (like also scrolling through twitter :P).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my previous post while writing about the different channels to market your Product, i missed newsletters. I think newsletters can turn out to be one of the best ways to do it. Few reasons why :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First of all you will find newsletters relating to almost any genre or group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The audience subscribing to a newsletter trust their host and their recommendations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can really target specific and niche people. Want to target developers ? Find a newsletter for developers. Want to target React developers ? Search for a newsletter that react devs read.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Communicate the value of your Product]]></title><description><![CDATA[Instead of spending 90% time on Building, Spend 90% time on Communicating the value proposition of your Product.]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me//posts/communicate-the-value-of-your-product</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://swissknife.me//posts/communicate-the-value-of-your-product</guid><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 17:40:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever had an idea which you thought, if only this was launched, it would be the next facebook or Tesla ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a bunch of such ideas that i keep compiling in my notes. Overtime, as i pitch them to friends and family, i notice that people are not convined and they don&apos;t even understand the value of it. Somewhere i miss communicating the value of the Product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today&apos;s post is precisely about this. How do you communicate the value of your Idea / Product ? You may have built the finest app in the world but if you cannot communicate the value that your idea brings into the life of the User (BTW : This is also the definition of Sales), it will all be a wasted effort. This has been my experience so far, after building a List sharing website, a mac menubar app and a fun product discovering Website. In all of these Products that i built, i was heads down into the Engineering side not worrying about bringing in Users or fine tuning my value proposition, needless to say the Products gained only a little traction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So a few days back, i had an idea about a chrome extension which would help Front-end devs in their Workflow. But this time i pulled myself to think about how to communicate the value of the Product to the Users. There were a couple of ways that i came up with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a mockup of the Product and attach screenshots of it on the Landing Page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a video, explaining the benefit of the Product to the developers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post it on the dev channels like Hackernews, dev.to etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get people to sign up for it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now if people did sign up, only than it would really make sense to build it. Also this will help me in getting some early users to build the Product.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Creating my own Gita]]></title><description><![CDATA[i am in essence, writing a Gita based on my Life, Values and Experiences. The only difference in my case is that i am the one figting the war (Arjun) and i am also the one Guiding him (Krishna).]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me//posts/creating-my-own-gita</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://swissknife.me//posts/creating-my-own-gita</guid><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 17:40:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;From the past week i have been watching videos on Youtube about Gita - what it teaches, the stories written in it, the life of Krishna and several other Characters in it. If you would have asked me about Gita or about any religion i would have given you the condescending looks of that of an Atheist. But this week, Gita and the lore of Krishna has taken my attention in a very pleasant manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of seeing it as a religious book, i finally realised that it actually details a way of life based on Ethics and Meaning. Based on the limited number of excerpts that i have listened to, i can say it feels very relevant and practical in today&apos;s modern life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gita was written in the backdrop of the great war of Mahabharata, where Arjun who is confused about what to do and is seeking the path of truth, is guided by Krishna, who helps him get Perspective, thereby enabling Arjun to go beyond his limitations. He serves as a mentor to Arjun and helps him reconcile all the Paradoxes in his head, which were crippling him to act and win the war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The similarities between me journaling daily on this website and Gita struck me suddenly.... Let me refraim this..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;With the Journaling, i am in essence, writing my version of Gita based on my Life, my Values and my Experiences. The only difference in my case is that i am the one figting the war (Arjun) as well as i am the one who is Guiding him (Krishna).&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Vanity and Sanity]]></title><description><![CDATA[Keeping Sanity and not going overboard with Vanity.]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me//posts/vanity-and-sanity</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://swissknife.me//posts/vanity-and-sanity</guid><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 17:40:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Today i will be writing about one of the areas in my life on which i actively think about and is something that i still struggle to resolve sometimes. It is about VANITY.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me explain...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have compared myself to others on the basis of looks and i also have certain part of my worth rooted in the way i look. It is because of this i have also felt less of a person than others some of the times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be able to present yourself neatly is important, but attributing your self woth to your looks is fleeting. It won&apos;t last forever and will be like playing a game you know you are destined to loose anyway. Instead i am working on to develop my own uniqueness and speaking my truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This brings me to story time...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long ago, There was a stoic Philosopher who used to wear weird looking clothes and would go against the fashion standards of his time. For Indians you can imagine Ranvir Singh :P. His philosophy was that we should never be ashamed of who we are / How we look and instead be only embarrased of ourselves if we had acted out of Character. So he would challenge himself by wearing ridiculous clothes and living that philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is a note to remind myself - &quot;Always be yourself and you are sufficient because you exist&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[writing every day]]></title><description><![CDATA[Committing to Writing a Post every single Day !]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me//posts/writing-every-day</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://swissknife.me//posts/writing-every-day</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 17:40:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking of writing for a while now. Writing for the purpose of just exploring my thoughts and articulate some of the things going inside my head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a long time i have delayed writing, because i have a notion that writing is hard and you have to spend considerable amount of time to get it perfect. So inorder to make a habbit of writing, i take this false assumption away which means the following :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starting from today i am going to commit to write a post every single day. This is a challenge that i have posed to myself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The idea is not to fret about the details or create polished articles. The meaning behind is to just pen down what you are thinking during the day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The format will be in a loose manner like i have written here. This is important as i want to reduce the barrier to entry considerably.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s start this journey. Cheers !&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[WhatsApp Non-Forwarding Feature]]></title><description><![CDATA[Picture this, you are renting out an Apartment and are required to send all the Documents for Proof. Now, the broker tells you to whatsapp your Aadhaar and PAN Card (Identification Documents Used in India) so that he can attach them. Here i become a bit hesitant at first to share my details, because of Privacy concerns.]]></description><link>https://swissknife.me//posts/whatsapp-non-forwarding-feature</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://swissknife.me//posts/whatsapp-non-forwarding-feature</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 17:40:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Picture this, you are renting out an Apartment and are required to send all the Documents for Proof. Now, the broker tells you to whatsapp your Aadhaar and PAN Card (Identification Documents Used in India) so that he can attach them. Here i become a bit hesitant at first to share my details, because of Privacy concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Possible Solution can be a &quot;Share Privately&quot; Option or a &quot;Non-Forwarding&quot; Option. So that the document or message is only seen by the party it was meant to be shared with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may also prevent Fake News on Whatsapp to some degree, as people generally tend to share sensitive content privately. This could potentially prevent misuse of that information.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>